{"Topic": "Circulatory System", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which of the following are the possible blood groups of the offspring of the parents with blood group O and AB?", "op1": "O, A, B and AB", "op2": "A and B", "op3": "A, B and AB", "op4": "O and AB", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "White blood cells act", "op1": "as a defence against infection", "op2": "as source of energy", "op3": "for clotting blood", "op4": "as a medium for oxygen transport from lung to tissues", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which one of the following is extra blood stored and is released when shortage occurs?", "op1": "Adrenal gland", "op2": "Pancreas", "op3": "Spleen", "op4": "Thyroid gland", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The average life span of red blood corpuscles is about", "op1": "100 - 200 days", "op2": "100 - 120 days", "op3": "160 - 180 days", "op4": "150 - 200 days", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "From which one of the following chambers of human heart is the oxygenated blood pumped into aorta?", "op1": "Right atrium", "op2": "Right ventricle", "op3": "Left atrium", "op4": "Left ventricle", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "If the radius of blood vessels of a person  decreases his/her blood pressure will", "op1": "increase", "op2": "decrease", "op3": "remain unaffected", "op4": "increase for males and decrease for females", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Insufficient blood supply in human body is referred as", "op1": "Ischemia", "op2": "Hyperemia", "op3": "Hemostasis", "op4": "Hemorrhage", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Mineral impurities in blood are removed by", "op1": "Lungs", "op2": "Kidney", "op3": "Spleen", "op4": "Liver", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Between which one of the following sets of blood groups, is the blood transfussion possible?", "op1": "A and O (A donor)", "op2": "B and A (B donor)", "op3": "A and AB (A donor)", "op4": "AB and O  (AB donor)", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The pH of Human Blood is ___?", "op1": "7.4", "op2": "7.2", "op3": "7.8", "op4": "6.6", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In the human body, red blood cells are produced in", "op1": "liver", "op2": "voluntary muscles", "op3": "pancreas", "op4": "bone marrow", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which is the anti-coagulant substance in blood?", "op1": "Fibrinogen", "op2": "Thrombin", "op3": "Globin", "op4": "Heparin", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What vessel carries the venous blood to the lungs for oxygenation?", "op1": "Pulmonary arteries", "op2": "Pulmonary veins", "op3": "Pulmonary arterio-venous shunt", "op4": "Right ventricle", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "When a child is born, what happens to its blood circulation?", "op1": "Its blood flows for the first time", "op2": "Its blood reverses its flow through the heart", "op3": "Its blood ceases to pass from one atrium to the other", "op4": "Its blood carries wastes for the first time", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the approximate time required for a heart-beat ?", "op1": "0.5 second", "op2": "0.8 second", "op3": "0.5 minute", "op4": "1.0 minute", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Universal receivers can receive blood from", "op1": "Group AB only", "op2": "Group O only", "op3": "Groups A, AB", "op4": "Groups O, A, B, AB", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Pulmonary artery carries", "op1": "pure blood from lungs", "op2": "pure blood to lungs", "op3": "impure blood to lungs", "op4": "impure blood from lungs", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Ions of which of the following minerals play an important role in blood clotting?", "op1": "Mg", "op2": "Na", "op3": "Ca", "op4": "K", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the condition in which heart is not pumping the blood effectively to meet the requirements of the body called?", "op1": "stroke", "op2": "hypertension", "op3": "myocardial infarction", "op4": "heart failure", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which part of the intestines is the digested food absorbed by the blood?", "op1": "Ileum", "op2": "Colon", "op3": "Jejenum", "op4": "Caecum", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Fastest distribution of some injectible material/medicine and with no risk of any kind can be achieved by injecting it into the", "op1": "muscles", "op2": "veins", "op3": "arteries", "op4": "lymph vessels", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Where does the impulse of heart beat originate?", "op1": "S.A. node", "op2": "A.V. node", "op3": "vagus nerve", "op4": "cardiac nerve", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following veins does not carry deoxygenated blood?", "op1": "hepatic vein", "op2": "hepatic portal vein", "op3": "renal vein", "op4": "pulmonary vein", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is instrument for measuring blood pressure called?", "op1": "electrocardiogram", "op2": "anemometer", "op3": "stethoscope", "op4": "sphygmanometer", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the percentage of water in blood plasma?", "op1": "90", "op2": "80", "op3": "98", "op4": "60", "Answer": 3}]}